二零二二年上海市初中学业水平考试英语第一部分听力部分即将开始。现在先试音，试音的内容是一段音乐，请注意调节音量和音调。下面请听音乐。
试音到此结束。听力部分现在开。开始。根据你听到的内容，选出相应的图片，并在答题纸上填涂相应的字母代号每个句子念两遍。
1. Mr. and Mrs.
Green enjoy taking a walk along the beach.
Mr. and Mrs.
enjoy taking a walk along the beach.
2. The boy has formed a habit of running every morning.
The boy has formed a habit of running every morning.
Lucy and Sam took a business trip to Beijing by plane.
4. Simon was excited that his friend came to visit him.
Simon was excited that his friend came to visit him.
5. The manager is busy with his daily office work.
The manager is busy with his daily office work.
根据你听到的对话和问题，选出最恰当的答案，并在答题纸上填涂相应的字母代号。对话和问题都。
6. Let's take a break.
Would you like something to drink, tea or coffee?
Question. What does the woman want?
再听一遍。
7. me, is there a bookstore here?
Yes, there's one on the fourth floor, next to the supermarket.
Thank you. is the man looking for?
Excuse me, is there a bookstore here in the shopping mall?
Yes, there's one on the fourth floor, next to the supermarket.
Thank you. is the man looking for?
8. Alan, do you know what time the museum opens?
It opens at 10 on weekdays and 9.30 on weekends.
Question. When does the museum open on weekdays?
请再听一遍。
9. Could I speak to Mr.
Smith? I'm sorry, he's giving a lecture online.
Can I take a message?
No, thanks. I'll call him later.
Question. What is Mr.
Smith doing? Could I speak to Mr.
Smith? I'm sorry, he's giving a lecture online.
Can I take a message?
No, thanks. I'll call him later.
is Mr. Smith doing?
10. Excuse me, I'd like to return this jacket.
there anything wrong?
I bought it for my son, but he doesn't like the style.
What is the possible relationship between the two speakers?
Excuse me, I'd like to return this jacket.
Is there anything wrong?
I bought it for my son, but he doesn't like the style.
What is the possible relationship between the two speakers?
Excuse me, like to wrong?
C. Saturday came.
判断句子是否符合你听到的短文内容，符合的用表示，不符合的用表示，并在答题纸上填涂相应的字母代号。短文念两遍。
It was a big day for Sarah's family.
There was going to be a party for Sarah's brother Peter.
He had just graduated from high school.
Early in the morning, Peter had a quick breakfast and left home in a hurry.
Sarah was still in bed when her mum came in.
Mum asked her to do the cleaning and decorate the living room.
Sarah was not happy to get up so early, but she agreed to help.
After breakfast, the parents started to prepare food for the party.
Sarah began to clean the house.
Several hours later, they finished all the work and were very tired.
Sarah wondered why her brother Peter did nothing for his own party.
At about five, Peter came back home and saw the decoration and the food.
He was so thankful for everything the family had done for his party.
He told the family excitedly that he did a few interviews and got a summer job that
day. this way, could help to pay for college.
Sarah realised it was also a busy day for Peter.
She gave him a big hug and said to him, enjoy the party.
再听一遍。
Saturday came. It was a big day for Sarah's family.
There was going to be a party for Sarah's brother Peter.
He had just graduated from high school.
Early in the morning, Peter had a quick breakfast and left home in a hurry.
Sarah was still in bed when her mum came in.
Mum asked her to do the cleaning and decorate the living room.
Sarah was not happy to get up so early.
But she agreed to help.
breakfast, parents started to prepare food for the party.
Sarah began to clean the house.
Several hours later, they finished all the work and were very tired.
Sarah wondered why her brother Peter did nothing for his own party.
At about five, Peter came back home and saw the decoration and the food.
He was so thankful for everything the family had done for his party.
He told the family excitedly that he did a interviews and got a summer job that day.
And in this way, he could help to pay for college.
Sarah realised it was also a busy day for Peter.
She gave him a big hug and said to him, enjoy the
听对话，用听到的单词完成句子。对话念两遍。
Frank, do you want to be my partner for the school project?
Sure, Kathy. I'm glad you asked me.
The project is to create a building with used materials.
Do you have I am thinking about making a mini tree house.
That sounds fun.
Then what about the materials,
I have some old gift boxes at home.
They can be used for the project.
Gift boxes? Good idea.
We can use them to make the base of the house.
Yes. Well, do you have any used materials, Frank?
My brother and I have saved some plastic bottles.
Great. Then when shall we start our project?
What about tomorrow?
Sorry, tomorrow I'll have a basketball game.
How about Friday?
Okay. Let's start on Friday.
I can do the cutting of the materials.
Do you want to do the painting?
Yeah, I'm pretty good at painting.
That's nice. I'm sure we will work well together.
You're right. I believe we'll make a good team.
I can't wait to start our project.
再听一遍。
Hey, Frank. Do you want to be my partner for the school project?
Sure, Kathy. I'm glad you asked me.
The project is to create a building with used materials.
Do you have any ideas?
I am thinking about making a mini tree house.
That sounds fun.
Then what about the materials,
I have some old gift boxes at home.
They can be used for the project.
Gift boxes? Good idea.
We can use them to make the base of the house.
Yes. Well, do you have any used materials, Frank?
Hmm. My brother and I have saved some plastic bottles.
Great. Then when shall we start our project?
What about tomorrow?
Sorry, tomorrow I'll have a basketball game.
How about Friday?
Okay. Let's start on Friday.
I can do the cutting of the materials.
Do you want to do the painting?
Yeah. I'm pretty good at painting.
That's nice. I'm sure we will work well together.
You're right. I believe we'll make a good team.
I can't wait to start our project.
听力测试结束，请关注“锦鲤英语”微信公众号
for watching.